Angshuman Mazumdar

I believe in a simple concept: if it's a piece of engineering, it is also a work of art. Also, an ardent follower of interactive media, especially video games, because they provide a great platform for experiences to flourish, unlike any other media.





angshuman.mazumdar@gmail.com



West Lafayette, Indiana



https://binaryvectorjr.github.io/

(585)-406-9165

in https://www.linkedin.com/in/angshuman-mazumdar-a0b75a130/

(o) https://binaryvectorjr.github.io/portfolio

EDUCATION

Master of Science (Computer Graphics Technology)

Purdue University, West Lafayette (Indiana) August 2019 – Expected May 2021 (GPA – 3.96)

Capstone Project

Rochester Institute of Technology, Rochester (New York) January 2019 – May 2019

Bachelor of Technology (Electronics and Communication)

Vellore Institute of Technology, Vellore 2015 - 2019 (CGPA - 8.69)

High School and Senior School

Don Bosco Senior Secondary School, Guwahati 2003 - 2015 (93.4%)

WORK EXPERIENCE

Trainee

Bharti Airtel 05/2018 - 06/2018 Chandigarh, India Achievements/Tasks

> Automated data collection and organization process for SACFA Applicants (using Visual Basic for Applications) which reduced the time for data organization significantly.

Graphic Designer

MOX - Movement of Expression 02/2018 - 08/2019 Shillong, India

Achievements/Tasks

- Designed the logos for the event "Street Sangam"
- Involved in their design process for various events

Assistant Editor

The Power of Connection (Documentary) 05/2020 - Present West Lafayette (IN, USA)

ACHIEVEMENTS

Graduate Teaching Assistant (Purdue University) (08/2020 -Present)

Responsible for assisting students with learning NX 12.0, for the course "Graphical Communication and Spatial Analysis"

Design Advisor for Team Vimaanas (01/2017 - 06/2018)

Team Vimaanas is the official Micro-Class RC Aviation team of VIT.

Design Head (BEAM-VIT) (06/2016 - 05/2017)

BEAM-VIT was a club of VIT University. Also held the position of Design Co-Chair for BIDSF 2017. BIDSF is an annual event organized by the Biotech Division of VIT.

SOFTWARE FAMILIARITY

Adobe Photoshop Adobe Illustrator Adobe Premiere Pro Adobe After Effects Unreal Engine 4 Unity3D World Machine Houdini Autodesk Maya Autodesk 3DS Max Blender Trimble SketchUp NX 12.0 C++HTML and CSS

Microsoft Office Suite (PowerPoint, Word, Excel)

MAJOR PROJECTS

Parkinson's Disease Assist Device using Machine Learning and Internet of Things (07/2017 - 04/2018)

- The main purpose of the project was to construct a prototype of a spoon which senses the hand motion of an individual suffering from Parkinson's disease.
- It gives a counter motion to the trembling actions of a patient's hand, in order that they don't spill their food.

Autonomous Robotic Manipulator (01/2019 – 04/2019)

- The goal was to develop the driver that will control a robotic arm manipulation of the larger project
- Final objective was to mount the arm to the top of an autonomous base, that could enable users to control it using Virtual Reality Techniques
- Application in the Elder Care Industry

Embodiment for the Difference: A VR Experience of Bipolar **Disorder** (08/2019 – 12/2019)

- The objective was to develop a simulation in virtual reality to provide an experience of the effects of Bipolar Disorder so as to make people aware of a few of the challenges a person suffering from bipolar disorder would have to face in their
- Platform used for delivering experience was Oculus Quest

LANGUAGES

Assamese	Native Language
English	Full Working Proficiency
Hindi	Bilingual Proficiency
French	Novice